永远别把龙舌兰酒和威士忌混在一起喝
Never mix tequila and scotch.
早上好  查理伯伯
Morning, Uncle Charlie.
杰克老兄
Jake, buddy.
爸爸说你一定起不来看我踢球的
Dad said you'd never get up to go to soccer with me.
但我说  他答应我的  看来他错了
But I said, he promised. So he was wrong.
什么?
What?
你知道吗  大多数父母穿短裤还抹防晒霜
You know, most of the parents wear shorts and lots of sunscreen,
不过你这样打扮也没问题
but that's another way to go.
艾伦  足球赛我去看不成  我刚从拉斯维加斯回来
Alan, I can't go to a soccer game. I just got home from Vegas.
你昨晚是去还录像带的呀
You went out last night to return a video.
我碰巧遇到个准备在美丽湖酒店结婚的朋友
I ran into a friend of mine who was getting married at the Bellagio.
难怪你会穿这身燕尾服
That explains the tuxedo.
不  我印象中穿这个好像是为了别的事儿
No, I think this was for something else entirely.
我相信我会在报纸上读到的
I'm sure I'll read about it in the paper.
我是这周负责足球赛供应点心的小二
Anyway, I am the Soccer Snack Buddy this week,
所以我得去趟杂货店
so I've gotta stop at the grocery store.
要不等车来了之后你和杰克去比赛场吧?
Why don't you ride to the game with Jake when the van gets here?
我有个更好的主意
I got a better idea.
我还是上楼呕吐之后  穿着衣服睡上12个小时好些吧?
Why don't I go upstairs, throw up and sleep in my clothes for 12 hours?
行啊  但如果你不去看比赛
Fine, but if you're not gonna come,
-你得自己跟杰克说去  -好啊  他会理解我的
-you gotta tell Jake yourself. -Fine. He'll understand.
-杰克?  -我有新鞋子啦
-Jake? -I got new cleats.
不错  听着  杰克  宝贝
Nice. Listen, Jake, buddy.
你有没有去过拉斯维加斯?
Have you ever been to Vegas?
你就是那个臭名昭著的查理伯伯?
So you're the infamous Uncle Charlie.
久仰大名
I've heard about you.
好汉两个半
第一季  第五集
所有人下车  小心碰头  一个接一个下
Everybody out. Watch your heads. One at a time.
-游戏时间  -快呀
-Party time. -Come on.
是这样的  查理伯伯  我觉得你很迷人
Here's the deal, Uncle Charlie. I find you attractive.
我有三个孩子  一个混球前夫
I have three kids, a bastard of an ex-husband,
一周在我自己开的旅行社工作50个小时
I work 50 hours a week at my own travel agency,
我现在是性高涨时期
I'm at the peak of my sexuality,
周三孩子们去学跆拳道的时候我有空
I have a three-hour window Wednesdays when the kids are at tae kwon do.
你意下如何?
You in or out?
不好意思  我宿醉后还没完全清醒而且刚还被鞋子踢到要害了
I'm sorry, I'm terminally hung over and I just took a cleat in the groin.
有空给我发邮件吧  人人都上歌罗瑞亚@aol.com
E-mail me. Allaboardgloria @aol.com.
哪一个是你家小孩?
So, which one's yours?
请不要让我讲话
Please don't make me talk.
这位是查理・哈勃  艾伦・哈勃的兄长
This is Charlie Harper. Alan Harper's brother.
-哪边赢家?  -没有赢家
-So, who's winning? -No one.
我们不计分的  我们认为小孩儿只是为了乐趣而玩比较健康
We don't keep score. We think it's healthier if the kids just play for fun.
你说笑呢  对吧?
You're yanking me, right?
朱蒂丝提醒我们说你是个刺头
Judith warned us that you were a pistol.
对了  我们对于她和艾伦的事感到遗憾
By the way, we were so sorry to hear about her and Alan.
跟我们说说  那是真的吗?
So tell us, is it true?
朱蒂丝真是因为别的女人才离开你弟弟的吗?
Did Judith leave your brother for another woman?
-你们干嘛不自己问朱蒂丝?  -我们不想太过八卦而已
-Why don't you ask Judith? -We wouldn't want to pry.
女士们  我失陪一下
Ladies, if you'll excuse me,
因为我得离开  见鬼  我干嘛要解释原因
I have to go because, hell, I don't need a reason.
有些人很自以为是嘛
Someone's a little full of himself.
不管他  赛场上的那个是他弟弟的小孩
Forget him. His brother's the one who's in play.
杰克怎么样了?
How's Jake doing?
杰克多好  他才十岁  他还有大好前程呢
Jake's fine. He's 10. He's got his whole life ahead of him.
而我  从另一方面讲
Me, on the other hand,
坐在大太阳下  穿着租来的裤子还得听着自己眨眼睛的噪音
I'm sitting in the hot sun, in rented pants listening to myself blink.
我还是问别人吧
I'll ask somebody else.
怎么了?
What?
抱歉  我忍不住偷听到  你看起来实在太
Sorry. I couldn't help overhearing, and you just look so
可悲了
pathetic.
是么?  晚礼服店的人说我看起来光彩夺目
Really? The guy at the tux shop said I looked dashing.
当然  那是昨天说的
Of course, that was yesterday.
之后我就在口袋里发现了他的电话号码
And I found his phone number in my pocket.
-什么情况?  -还录影带而已
-What was the occasion? -Just returning a video.
-查理・哈勃  -凯特・麦克拉林
-Charlie Harper. -Kate McLaughlin.
让我来问你几个问题  凯特・麦克拉林
Let me ask you something, Kate McLaughlin.
你对于比赛不计分这事儿怎么看?
What's your take on this whole no-keeping-score thing?
我觉得这是我见过最蠢的事儿
I think it's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
我能坐你旁边吗  这里比较安全
Can I stay here next to you where it's safe?
可以啊
Sure.
哪个是你家小孩?
So, which one's yours?
九号  不过我不是他爸
Number nine. But I'm not the father.
看来你不擅长运动啊
Aren't you a good sport?
杰克  我再说最后一次
Jake, for the last time,
没有人"兴奋"  没人赢也没人输
nobody got "creamed." No one won, no one lost.
好啊  除了我们  12比2
Yeah. Except for us. 12-2.
输赢并不重要  重要的是你有没有被痛宰
It doesn't matter if you win or lose. It's whether or not you beat the spread.
真是谢谢你了  查理  杰克  洗澡去
Thank you, Charlie. Jake, go take a shower.
查理  我们在教孩子不要去计分
Charlie, we are trying to teach the kids not to keep score.
你在教他们数数前应该想到这个
You should've thought of that before you taught them to count.
顺便问一下  你和杰克明天有什么安排?
By the way, what are you doing with Jake tomorrow?
没计划呢  怎么啦?
I don't know. Why?
我帮他和球队的孩子约了个"游玩日"
I made a play date for him with one of the kids from the game.
你想吊人家小孩的妈了  对吧?
You're hitting on the mother, aren't you?
什么都逃不过你的法眼  对吧?
Can't slip one past you, can I?
"游玩日"不该是为了这个
That's not what a play date is for.
怎么?  小孩可以玩  我也可以约会  一举多得啊
What? The kid plays, I have a date. Everybody wins.
-一举多得?  -是呀
-Everybody wins? -Yes.
但我保证不计分好吧
But I promise not to keep score.
查理  你不能利用我儿子去钓单身母亲的
Charlie, you cannot use my son to pick up single mothers.
但我可以
But I can.
晚安  点心大叔
Good night, Snack Buddy.
不准去水边  不准扔石头  还有记住
No going in the water, no throwing rocks, and remember,
如果你们看不到我们  我们也看不到你们
if you can't see us, we can't see you.
你还有什么要补充的  查理?
Is there anything you'd like to add, Charlie?
-为什么他们不能扔石头?  -玩去吧
-Why can't they throw rocks? -Go.
厄尼喜欢在海滩玩  谢谢你邀请他
Ernie loves the beach. Thanks for inviting him.
为了孩子怎么都好  他们可是我们的未来
Anything for the kids. They're our future.
-艾伦在哪儿呢?  -我让他看电影去了
-So, where's Alan? -I sent him to the movies.
他应该休息休息  这样我也可以好好陪陪杰克
He deserves a break, and I get some quality uncle time with Jake.
我觉得你人真好
I think that is really nice of you.
厄尼  别脱鞋袜
Ernie, keep your socks with your shoes.
抱歉  说到哪儿了?
I'm sorry, where was l?
你说我人很好之类的
You were saying I was nice about something.
你在雪曼橡树区住了多久啦?
How long have you lived in Sherman Oaks?
我们搬来有...  厄尼  把那个放下  那是死的
We moved in and... Ernie, put that down, it's dead.
小孩什么都捡  无论那东西看起来像什么
That kid'll pick up anything, no matter what it looks like.
明白
Been there.
我们搬来的时候正好赶上地震...
Anyway, We moved in just in time for the earthquake...
厄尼  我不会再说一遍了
Ernie, I am not gonna say it again.
把那个死东西放下
Put the dead thing down.
杰克  你可能也该把你那个死东西放下
Jake, you should probably put your dead thing down, too.
-小孩嘛  -我明白  他们只是...
-Kids. -I know. They're just...
厄尼  把那放下否则我们立马离开
Ernie, put it down or we're leaving right now.
我数到三  一  二
I'm counting to three. One, two...
厄尼  求你了  我要被你整死了
Ernie, for God's sake, you're killing me here.
-谢谢  -不客气
-Thank you. -No problem.
-你在洛杉矶长大的吗?  -不是
-So, did you grow up in L.A.? -No.
我爸参了军所以我们搬到...
My dad was in the Army so we moved around...
见鬼  那东西还没死
Hell, that thing's not dead.
我很希望深入了解你  但带着孩子绝对不行
I'd like to get to know you, it's not gonna happen on a play date.
-不如改天约我好了?  -那真是太好...
-why donn't you ask me out sometime? -That's a really good...
你满意了吧?  我早让你放下的  厄尼
Are you happy? I told you to put it down, Ernie.
把沙子拍掉  别  别碰它
Get the sand off of it. No. Don't touch it.
-你哪天有空啊?  -杰克  你别帮倒忙了
-What night's good for you? -Jake, you're not helping.
-不要等我啦  -回拉斯维加斯呀?
-Don't wait up. -Back to Vegas?
比那儿更好  雪曼橡树区
Even better. Sherman Oaks.
通往凡奈之路(加利福尼亚)
The gateway to Van Nuys.
又是凯特?
Kate again?
查理  你根本不知道牵扯上这些足球小子的妈妈
Charlie, You have no clue what you're getting involved in
-会有什么结果  -你说的没错
-with these divorced soccer moms. -You're right.
我是不明白  也没明白过  这就是我的魅力之所在
I don't have a clue. I've never had a clue. It's part of my charm.
那至少记住这些妇女会互通有无的
At least keep in mind that all these women talk to each other.
所以不管你做什么  都会传到我老婆那儿
So anything you do will get back to my wife,
最后无端变成我的错
and somehow become my fault.
这貌似不公平
That doesn't seem fair.
你要干嘛去?
So, where are you going?
我去帮歌罗瑞亚弄足球联盟的简报
I'm helping Gloria with the soccer league newsletter.
我想命名为"只为踢球"
I'm thinking of calling it "Just For Kicks."
等等  这和开车送小孩的歌罗瑞亚是同一个人么?
wait a minute. This is the same Gloria who drives the kid van?
-是呀  怎么啦?  -没什么  玩的愉快
-Yeah. Why? -Nothing. Have fun.
走着瞧  看谁不明白
Talk about not having a clue.
我设计了一个标识
And I designed a logo,
"踢"的偏旁旁边有个小脚丫
the "K" in "Kicks" is a little foot.
听起来不错
Sounds wonderful.
让你花时间来做这个我真是不知道怎么感谢你
I can't thank you enough for taking the time to do this.
为了孩子嘛
Anything for the kids.
你真是个好父亲
You're such a good father.
朱蒂丝不懂得欣赏你是她的损失
It's a shame that Judith didn't appreciate you.
她只是需要点时间整理思绪
She just needed a little time to sort things out.
但没错  是她的损失
But, yeah. It's a shame.
看看你
Look at you.
一个成功的脊椎按摩师  集智慧和细心于一身
A successful chiropractor, intelligent, dedicated.
说的我都不好意思了
You're embarrassing me.
抱歉啦
I'm sorry.
咱们还是说说你的小标识吧
Let's get back to your little logo.
-怎么啦?  -没事儿
-What's wrong? -Nothing.
是我的脖子  大概睡姿有问题吧
It's my neck. I must have slept wrong.
到我诊所预约好了  我看看能不能治好
Make an appointment with my office, we'll see if we can fix that.
别呀  我会不好意思的
No, I'd feel funny.
我们可认识对方呀
We know each other.
别傻了  那是我该做的
Don't be silly. It's what I do.
转身  转过去  转吧
Turn around. Turn around. Go ahead.
-你补钙补得够着呢吧?  -是吧
-Are you getting enough calcium? -I guess.
钙质对于你这个年纪的女人很重要的
It's really important for a woman your age.
骨质疏松可是个严重问题
Osteoporosis is a real problem.
还有椎间盘突出啦
Curvature of the spine.
你肯定不想变成驼背吧
Last thing you want is to wind up with a hump.
希望你们没在我来之前就开始了
I hope you didn't start without me.
-你说什么呢?  -比尔  你是故意那么做的
-What are you talking about? -Bill, you did this on purpose.
你故意来晚好能偷偷监视我
You showed up late so you could snoop on me.
-你见过我女朋友了啊  -什么呀  她是我们的保姆
-You got to meet my girlfriend. -What meet? She was our babysitter.
你能不能给我滚出去  比尔?
Will you get out of here, Bill?
凯特  我也想呀  厄尼  能不能把鞋穿上?
Kate, I'm trying. Ernie, would you put your shoes on?
-比尔  -查理
-Bill. -Charlie.
那是你的捷豹(福特跑车)?
That your Jag?
-是呀  -不错
-Yeah. -It's nice.
我的领航者(林肯越野车)在那儿
I got the Navigator over there.
也很不错嘛
That's nice, too.
走吧  老爸
Let's go, Dad.
那就这样吧  你想办法哄她开心好了
All right, then. You try and make her happy.
事实上  我觉得吓到我前夫的是
Truthfully, I think that my ex was intimidated
我的性的...
by my sexual...
我不知道该怎么说  胃口吧
I don't even know, how to say it. Appetite.
所以我们都同意了编辑区旁留六英寸?
So we're agreed we'll set aside six inches for the editorial column?
抱歉哈  是的  六英寸
I'm sorry. Yes, six inches.
我不知道怎么就跑题了
I don't know how I got so off-topic.
我很清楚你是怎么跑题的
I know exactly how you got off-topic.
好了  我想下来该决定纸的颜色了
ok. I think the next piece of business is to decide on the paper color.
我带了些样本  我们有
I brought some samples. We've got
菊花色  鲑鱼色  芥末色...
goldenrod, salmon, mustard...
听到你说小菊花我就动心了
You had me at goldenrod.
人人都知道你喜欢小菊花
Everybody has you at goldenrod.
我弟弟艾伦提醒我今晚不要和你约会
My brother, Alan, warned me not to go out with you tonight.
真有趣
That's funny.
每个人都提醒我不要和你出来约会
Everybody warned me not to go out with you.
对罗密欧和朱丽叶来说就没问题
It worked for Romeo and Juliet,
直到他们喝下毒药和自杀之前
up until the poison and the stabbing.
查理  我要坦白件事儿
Charlie, I have a confession.
十二年来除了我老公我没和其他男人约会过
I haven't been out with a man other than my husband in 12 years.
这不是问题
That's not a problem.
虽然很多事变了  但我可以帮你跟上时代的步伐
A couple of things have changed, I can bring you up to date.
愿闻其详
Please do.
好吧  如今的用餐都是女人付账
All right, well, nowadays, women pay for dinner.
当然  饭后嘿咻是死规定
And of course, sex is a given.
那我至少要告诉你  我是不会为晚餐付账的
I'll tell you one thing, I am not paying for dinner.
可恶
Rats.
时间不早  我们也该走了
Look at the time. Maybe we should get going.
在歌罗瑞亚那么多孩子回来之前
Give Gloria a chance for a little quiet time before
我们还是让她享受一下这片刻的宁静吧
her many, many kids come home.
我不需要宁静
I don't need any quiet time.
别傻啦
Don't be silly.
艾伦  你介不介意送我回家啊?
Alan, would you mind driving me home?
我有点儿醉意
I'm feeling a little tipsy.
有点儿醉意?  是有点明显吧?
A little tipsy? How about a little obvious?
-你说什么?  -我能单独跟你谈谈么?
-I'm sorry? -Could I talk to you for a minute?
-时间不早了  -给我坐下
-lt is getting a little late. -Sit down.
我们马上回来
We'll be right back.
我觉得她是更年期综合征
I think she's going through the change.
-你以为你在干什么?  -什么?
-What do you think you're doing? -What?
他在我的游戏之中  我掌控着游戏
He's in play. I'm playing.
是我告诉你他在游戏之中的吧
I'm the one who told you he's in play.
拜托  两年前我就告诉过你他的婚姻快黄了
Please. I told you two years ago that marriage was toast.
那又怎样?
So what?
周三跆拳道的空档他在我家
He's in my house on tae kwon do Wednesday,
我没时间跟你胡闹
and I don't have time to mess around with you.
我们不如让他决定好了?
Why don't we just let him decide?
让他决定?
Let him decide?
他还以为我们在做足球简报呢
He still thinks we're doing a soccer newsletter.
-你甚至都不喜欢他  不是吗  -他还好啦
-You don't even like him, do you? -He's okay.
他在这儿而且又是周三
He's here and it's Wednesday.
我正好觉得他很性感
I happen to think he's hot.
性感的家伙你应付不来的
You wouldn't know what to do with a hot guy.
是么?  瞧我的吧
Yeah? Well, watch me.
很好  你把他弄坏了
Great. You broke him.
最意外的是我喜欢他在我身边
The biggest surprise was how much I loved having him around.
我是说杰克很棒
I mean, Jake's amazing.
你知道吗  我有时候会把他的需求放在我的之前?
Do you know I have, on occasion, actually put his needs ahead of my own?
就像是周六早上八点看球赛?
Like going to a soccer game at 8:00 am on a Saturday?
没错
Yes.
早上八点我连下床去厕所都难
At 8:00 am, I can barely get out of bed to go to the bathroom.
你是说在你的生命中有个孩子
What you're saying is having a child in your life
完全改变的你看待事物的方式
totally changes the way you look at things.
就是这样
Exactly.
当然  也许你已经知道了
Of course, you probably know that already.
但我很高兴你也知道
But I like that you know it.
-今晚很愉快  -我也是
-I had a really great time. -Me, too.
-我们能再出来玩吗  -我很乐意啊
-Can we do this again? -I would love that.
太好了
Great.
发生什么事儿了?  我做错什么了吗?
What happened? Did I do something wrong?
千万别告诉艾伦他老婆
Please don't tell Alan's wife.
不  你什么也没做错
No, you didn't do anything wrong.
我真的很喜欢你
I really like you.
好吧  这对我还是新鲜事儿
Okay. This is new for me.
只是...
It's just...
查理  我有个十岁的儿子
Charlie, I have a 10-year-old son.
还有两份抵押贷款  私立学校的账单
I have two mortgages, private school bills,
一份全职工作  还要争取监护权  赡养费
a full-time job, custody battles, alimony battles,
育儿费  还要拼车去上鼓课
child support battles, car pools and drum lessons.
我们怎么可能再出来约会?
How can we possibly do this again?
你给十岁的小孩子买了架子鼓?
You bought a 10-year-old a drum set?
别转移话题  你知道我在说什么
Don't change the subject. You know what I'm saying.
你真的想牵扯进来吗?
Do you really want to be involved in this?
我还真没想那么远
I hadn't really thought that far ahead.
没错
Exactly.
好啦  我们改天见吧
All right. I guess I'll see you around.
你去哪儿呀?
Where are you going?
-回家呀  -为什么?
-Home. -Why?
我说我们不能再约  可那不代表我们今晚
I said we couldn't do it again. That doesn't mean we can't
也不能做
do it tonight.
老兄  你还真是什么都不明白  对吧  查理?
Boy, you really don't have a clue, do you, Charlie?
不明白
No.
不过似乎对我很管用
But it seems to be working for me.
早上好
Morning.
一般咖啡还是低咖啡因的?
Regular or decaf?
-一般的吧  -谢天谢地
-Regular. -Thank God.
你都不好奇吗?
Aren't you even curious?
-你昨晚去歌罗瑞亚家了嘛  -是呀
-You went to Gloria's last night. -Yeah.
其他就不言自明了
I can fill in the blanks.
我们输惨了
We're getting killed.
我们是来玩的  对吧?  不分输赢的
We're here for fun, right? Nobody wins or loses.
得了吧  有人老输
Come on. Somebody always loses.
我们要骗谁呀?
Who are we kidding?
已经是8比1了，大家都心知肚明
It's 8-1 out there, and everybody here knows it.
知道吗  我还要说一件事儿
And you know, I'll tell you another thing.
我们这季都没有赢过
We haven't won a game all season.
而且我会把它写入简报的
And I'll put that in the newsletter.
老天作证
And as God as my witness,
简报一定会有的!
there will be a newsletter!
老爸  你吓到大家了
Dad, you're kind of freaking everybody out here.
别管他  杰克  这里是雪曼橡树区
Forget it, Jake. It's Sherman Oaks.